好了
Okay.
治"聊"吧
"Therafy" me.
你迟了
You're late.
你肥了
You're fat.
这有点反常啊
It's unusual.
知道停车场离这多远么?
You know how far the parking lot is?
我腿疼
My leg's been hurting.
最近有所纠结 有压力?
Anything been on your mind lately,any particular stress?
没有 好像要下雨了
No.Probably just gonna rain.
等候室添了一幅莫奈的复制品 睡莲 你觉得怎样?
You like the new Monet reproduction in the waiting room-- the Water Lilies?
我来晚了
I was late.
没工夫欣赏室内装饰 不过听起来挺温婉舒缓的
I wasn't focusing on the decor,but it sounds appropriately bland and calming.
压力可能导致心不在焉
Stress can also  make you absentminded.
我没压力 你一个劲说我压力重重 倒真给我添了不少
I'm not stressed... Beyond the stress induced by you telling me how stressed I am.
只是平常的一周?
Just an ordinary week.
那好
Okay.
给我讲讲
Tell me about it.
我接了个病人
I had a patient.
House
House.
来的正好 有个病例给你 (又意: 箱子)
Good.I have a case for you.
一箱啤酒?
Beer?
失忆症
Amnesia.
被发现时她正在跑步 突然失去方向感 差点被卡车撞了
She was found jogging in the street,disoriented.She almost got hit by a truck.
MRI检测无异常
The MRI showed no abnormalities.
她没带身份证件
No I.D. on her.
只穿了运动服 带着心率表
Just her jogging clothes  and her heart rate monitor.
我们对她一无所知
We know absolutely nothing about her.
至少知道她很有钱
We know she has money.
Blaze Outriggers 400块一双
Blaze outriggers-- 400 bucks a pair.
有钱人不会就此失踪的
People who have money  don't just disappear.
早晚会有人来找她
Sooner or later,someone's gonna show up looking for her.
- 给我点吃的好吗? - 她15分钟前刚吃过
- Can I have something to eat? - She just ate 15 minutes ago.
她总是忘了
She keeps forgetting.
你想吃饭并非因为到了吃饭时间
You don't eat because you remember it's time to eat.
而是受饥饿驱使 她的新陈代谢正高速运转
You eat 'cause you're hungry.Her metabolism is in high gear.
- 她经常长距离跑步 - 你去急诊室干嘛?
- She is an extreme long-distance runner-- Why were you in the ER?
你就问这个?
That's your question?
我声情并茂地讲好玩的失忆病例 你作为心理医师只关心我的方位?
You're a psychotherapist.You're hearing about a great amnesia case,and all you're asking me is geography.
好奇而已
Just curious.
我在躲着Wilson
I was avoiding Wilson.
这事还是能躲则躲
It's not something you couldn't have seen eight miles away.
Wilson是个特婆妈的人
Wilson's a processor.
我知道他有事要向我摊牌 开口就很墨迹
I knew there were  some things  that he'd want  to process with me...  At length.
Sam要搬来住
Sam's moving in.
如果你周五前提出 你助理就赢了
If it's before Friday,your assistant wins the pool.
我只想问问你有什么打算
I was just wondering what your plans were.
- 今晚? - 后半辈子
- Tonight? - In life.
- Sam挺喜欢你 - 但她想让我搬出去
- Sam likes you... - But she wants me to move out.
不 是我想让你搬出去
No.I want you to move out.
我没想到我和Sam进展会这么迅速
I didn't know things with Sam would happen so quickly.
我没-- 这节骨眼上我不想犯错
I didn't-- I don't want to make a mistake here.
- 我已经犯了不少了 - 因为你进展太快
- I've made a lot of mistakes. - By moving too quickly.
按你的正常频率 我很惊讶你们还未梅凋二度
Given your usual rate of commitment,I'm surprised you're not already re-divorced.
我可以帮你另找个房子
I could help you find a place.
我原来的房子怎么了?
What's wrong with my old place?
没 我以为... 你想找个新地方 一个...
Nothing.I just thought... You might want to find somewhere new,somewhere...
我没在那嗑过药和产生幻觉的地方
Where I didn't abuse drugs and hallucinate.
对
Yes.
我很好
I'm fine.
你很好?
You're fine?
铁哥们把你扫地出门 你却很好?
Your best friend is tossing you out,and you're fine?
有什么可郁闷的?
Why wouldn't I be?
你没感到一丝... 背叛和愤怒?
You're not feeling  a little...  betrayed and angry?
Wilson买这两卧的公寓 就是为了你能搬去一起住
Wilson bought a two-bedroom condo specifically so that you could move in with him.
这才没多久
It wasn't that long ago.
你没觉得... 被耍了?
You don't feel a little... jerked around?
他没法预料Sam会重投他的怀抱
He couldn't foresee Sam coming back into his life.
你替朋友做的这番辩护很有道理
That's a very rational defense of your friend.
但我不信
And,uh,I'm not buying it.
凭什么不信?
Based on what?
就凭你来晚了 也没留意外面的新画
Based on the fact that you were late,and you didn't notice the pictures in the outer office.
- 这又不是症状 - 对我来说是
- Those aren't symptoms. - They are to me.
还有一点 你接了那病例对吧?
And here's another one.You took the case.Hmm?
没商量 没提条件
No negotiating,no bargaining.
没借机减少门诊任务
No clinic hours changed hands.
你是想转移注意力 以免纠结于好友赶你出门?
Were you looking for something to distract you from the fact that your best friend just threw you out?
- 那病例够好玩 - 这既不是机能问题 又非医学谜题
- Case was interesting. - It's not organic.It's not mysterious.
很可能是心理创伤导致 病人的大脑选择失忆以自卫
Most likely some psychologically traumatic event occurred that made the patient's brain choose to forget everything.
非也
Or not.
这里
Here.
脑灰质和白质间无分化
Loss of differentiation between gray and white matter.
这无大碍
That's subtle.
但恰在记忆区 不会只是巧合的
But it's in the area that controls memory.Not likely it's a coincidence.
细菌感染?
Bacterial infection?
我有必要知道这些吗?
Do I need to know this?
好吧 简单概括 Chase认为是多发性硬化
Fine.I'll give you the cliff notes version-- chase--m.S.
Taub认为是外伤 都被排除了 你想知道原因我可以告诉你
Taub--physical trauma.I can tell you why we ruled them out.
不想
Or not.
可能是毒素所致 得尽快找到致病源头 我们该检查一下她家
It's probably a toxin,and we need to find it before it kills her.We should search her House.
祝你好运
Good luck with that.
她的心率表上刻有序列号
Her heart rate monitor has a serial number.
根据它 经销商可以查出哪家店出售
The distributor  can match the number  to the store that sold it.
她那运动的劲头 肯定常进出那家店 店员也许能认出她
She's a serious athlete.She might have been there often enough to be remembered.
厉害
Brilliant.
他真那么说了?
Did he really say that?
- 潜台词 - 这方法不靠谱
- Subtextually. - Long shot.
就算店员不认识她 商店也可能在她住处附近
Even if the store clerk doesn't know who she is,the store's probably close to where she lives.
她看到周边景象说不定会想起什么
Just seeing those surroundings might spark a memory.
你要我们带她去?
You want us to take her there?
不 我带她去
No. I'll take her.
真的?
Really?
亲自接触病人 这不是你风格吧?
Uh,it's unusual for you to spend time with a patient,isn't it?
病人都很无聊... 人人如此
Patients are boring... As people.
这病人也不例外 但她处境很有意思
This one I'm sure was no exception,but her situation was interesting.
再说 我仍避着Wilson
Besides,I was still avoiding Wilson.
离开医院是最好的办法
And no better way to avoid than leaving the hospital.
也许吧
Maybe.
或者你是不想回家?
Or were you avoiding going home?
人们让瘾君子远离老巢自有道理
There's a reason they tell addicts to stay away from old geography.
不是不想回去 我回去过了 就在那天上班之前
I wasn't avoiding going home.I'd already gone home... Before I came into work that day.
我出了Wilson家门就直奔那了
I went straight there from Wilson's.
喂 轻点儿! 草菅人命啊!
Hey,take it easy!You're gonna kill me!
天呐 什么人啊门都不敲? House 是你! 你去哪了?
God,why don't people  knock?House,it's you!Where you been?
等一下
Hold up a second.
Alvie?
Juan Alvarez 你让他住你那?
Juan alvarez-- you let him stay at your place?
没有
Not exactly.
我都怀疑你是不是永远不回来了
I was beginning to wonder if you were ever gonna show up.
你的家 我的家 家!
Su casa,mi casa.Casa!
你怎么在这?
Why are you here?
我出院后就回到老住处了
When I left Mayfield,I went back to the old neighborhood.
对了 你浴室窗户忘锁了
You know,you shouldn't leave the bathroom window unlocked.
多谢你的安全小贴士 你来干嘛?
Yeah,thanks for the safety lesson.Why are you here?
就像我说的 我回到原住处 发现移民局正四处找我
Like I said,when I went back to the neighborhood,I found out immigration was looking for me.
我就来老伙计House家串门了!
So I decided to visit my old buddy House!
我家被你糟践得像件超大码囚服
And turn his apartment into a giant prison jumpsuit.
我Juan Alvarez可不是吃白饭的 我干活来换借宿
Juan alvarez is no freeloader.I do my part,earn my keep.
刚来第一周我给你做饭 你没回来
The first week I made your dinner,but you never showed up.
第二周我把你的东西都整了一遍
The second week  i organized your stuff.
- 我的东西? - 但你还是没回来
- My stuff? - But still,you never showed up.
所以本周 鉴于我粉刷本领强 就决定...
So this week,since I'm a real good painter,i decided to--
咖啡桌-- 你把它放哪了?
coffee table-- where'd you put it?
卧室?
In the bedroom?
颜料贵着呢 House 这可是定制的
The paint's not cheap,House.It's a custom color.
混合了钛色 黄色和赭石色
It's a mix of titanium,yellow,and ochre.
赭石... 我其实一点不喜欢 看上去像水果 上面还有毛
Ochre--I don't even like that stuff.It's like a fruit.It's got hair on it.
- 不过他们说这是蔬菜... - 你卖了我的咖啡桌换我不要的涂料?
- But they say it's a vegetable-- you sold my table to pay for paint that I don't want?
我还卖了点别的
I had to sell some other things too.
- 让开 - 不要 拜托 刷了试试看啊
- Get out. - No,papa,just give the color a chance.
我现在去上班
Look,I'm going to work now.
等我回来时 最好墙的颜色 别这么非主流 你也给我消失
And when I come back,the walls will be a less exciting color,and you will be gone.
Wilson把你赶走 你把Alvie赶走 你还说这周很平常?
So Wilson threw you out,and you threw alvie out-- just,uh,another week?
区别是 Alvie赶不走 那天我骑摩托车上班
Unlike me,alvie didn't leave.I took my motorcycle to work that day.
等我回家取汽车时 他把天花板漆成了绛红色
When I went home to get my car,he was painting the ceiling magenta.
所以我把他绑身边 免得他糟蹋我房子
So I brought him with me to protect the apartment.
为什么?
Why?
免得他糟蹋我房子 这话听着耳熟
To protect the apartment.Deja vu.
把他赶走 或支他去看电影
Tossing him out  or,uh,sending him to the movies or,
或关在卫生间 都能约束Alvie的破坏力
uh,locking him in the bathroom would also minimize alvie's destructive force.
你却让他呆在你身边 为什么?
But you chose his company deliberately.Why?
显然因为他可以代替Wilson
Obviously because  he's a Wilson substitute.
他们简直是一个模子印出来的 尤其Wilson说唱时
You can barely tell the difference between them,especially when Wilson raps about the hood.
我不是说Alvie是替代品 但他能极大地转移你的注意力
I'm not suggesting alvie's a substitute,but he would make a great distraction.
- 转移什么注意力? - 正是我想知道的
- From what? - That's what I'm trying  to find out.
继续说
Go on.
也许心率表是别人送她的礼物
Maybe the heart rate monitor was a gift.
所以没人认得她
That's why no one recognized her.
闭嘴 Alvie
Shut up,alvie.
有什么熟悉的吗... 教堂 杂货店?
Anything familiar... Church,grocery store?
抱歉
Sorry.
不要紧 也许X小姐从没来过镇上 心率表是网店买的
It's okay,Ms.x.Maybe she's never been to this town before,bought the heart rate monitor on the store's website.
你知道波多黎各人是美国公民吧?
You know that puerto ricans are U.S. citizens,right?
与其插手病例  你怎么不处理下你的身份问题?
Instead of working the case,why don't you contemplate the inanity of an American with American immigration issues?
我本来有出生证明 但弄丢了
I had a birth certificate.I lost it.
- 那办张新的 - 我去办了 House
- So get a new one. - I tried that,House.
但我小时候市政厅有过火灾  档案都烧毁了
But the town hall had burned down when I was a kid,destroyed the records.
他们只有一份?
There's only one copy?
他们要我搞定一堆表格 才肯再发一份
They tried to make me fill out a whole bunch of forms before they'd give it to me.
所以我决定自己DIY
I decided it would be quicker and easier to do it myself.
然后呢?
How'd that go?
他们发现是假的 现在不管我说什么他们都不信了
They figured out it was forged.And now,for some reason,they don't believe anything I say.
他们连我是波多黎各人都不信了
They actually think I'm lying about being puerto rican.
要我去一个特别听证会证实
Told me I had to go to a special hearing to prove it.
如果没一样看着眼熟呢?
What if nothing ever looks familiar?
没准你的丈夫 朋友会出现 告诉你是谁 是什么样一个人
Then someone will show up-- a spouse,a friend-- to tell you who you really are and what you should be feeling.
他们会出现的
They always do.
我不知道他是谁... 但我很想他
I don't know who that is... But I miss him.
他们在听证会上怎么说?
What did they say at the hearing?
我没去 我撒过一次谎了
I didn't go.I lied once.
你妈妈是波多黎各人 你自然也是波多黎各人
Your mother is puerto rican,therefore,you are puerto rican.
你只要证明你妈是你亲妈 找点证明文件...
All you got to do is prove your mom's your mom,find some documentation--
他们那种人是听不进我的话的
people like that don't listen to people like me.
甜甜圈! House 我们买点甜甜圈吧!
Doughnuts!Hey,House,let's get doughnuts!
- Alvie 听证会...  - 所有人都喜欢甜甜圈...
- Alvie,the hearing-- everyone loves doughnuts--
糖衣的 油炸的 象耳朵 还有里头的洞洞
glazed,crullers,elephant ears,even doughnut holes.
比运动商品店有爱多了 我打赌X小姐一定常去
Much better than the sporting goods store.I went Mrs.x went there all the time.
我们不是来... 我突然想到... 你说到点子上了...
We're not here-- And then I realized...  You make a good point.
真的? 我瞎扯的
Really?I was making that up.
一打糖衣的 一打果酱的?
Dozen glazed,dozen jelly-filled?
照老样子来一份?
You want the usual,right?
你的老朋友 油炸碳水化合物
Your old friend,the fried carbohydrate.
她需要高热量食物支持她的运动量 你知道她叫什么吗?
She needed the calorically dense food to support the running habit.Do you know her name?
Sandy... 还是Shelley来着
Sandy... Or shelley.
不清楚 我听过和他同来的男人 这么叫她 我在这儿工作而已
I don't know.The guy she's with  called her that once.I just work here.
知道她住哪吗?
Do you know where they live?
他留下一张名片 参加免费甜甜圈抽奖
He left a business card in our free doughnut jar.
在中奖告示墙上
It's up on the wall of winners.
Sidney
Sidney.
天哪 我好担心你
God,I was so worried about you.
发生什么事了?
What happened?
警察说采取行动还过早  我就自己给医院打电话
The police said it was too soon to do anything,so I started calling  hospitals on my own.
普林斯顿教学医院不在我的清单上
Princeton Plainsboro  wasn't even on my list.
你觉得这里某件东西让她得病了?
You really think  something around here  could have made her sick?
这里 工作的地方 任何她去过的地方
Here,work,anywhere  she could have been exposed.
为什么普林斯顿教学医院不在清单上?
Why wasn't Princeton Plainsboro on your list?
要跑很远 即便是对她而言
Well,I mean,it's a long way to run,even for her.
我除了跑步还干什么?
What is it I do besides run?
你是律师 处理民事纠纷 共同起诉的案子
You're a lawyer-- civil rights,class action suits.
工作压力很大
It's a stressful job.
跑步是你缓解压力的方式
Running's the way you deal with it.
听起来不太像我
That doesn't sound like me.
你觉得你应该是什么样的人?
Do you have any idea  what would sound like you?
好问题
Good point.
当时你在想什么?
So what were you thinking  during all this?
我当时的处境很微妙
That it was a strange  position to be in.
她对我比对她丈夫还亲近
At that moment,she was  more comfortable with me  than with her husband.
他开始觉得不安
And he was picking up  on it.
那你呢?
What about you?
我怎么了?
What about me how?
那你觉得你们之间 有没建立起这种亲密关系?
Well,there was a sort of,um,artificial intimacy between you?
她依赖你 某程度上 你会不会被这种依赖吸引?
She'd been  dependent on you.Uh,did you find that  attractive on some level?
还是觉得困扰?
Disturbing?
我只有这两个选择?
Those are my two choices?
两个都不是
None of the above.
她只是个病人 我觉得她有意思罢了
She was just a patient.She was interesting.
我们真的...结婚了?
So we're really... Married?
结婚四年了
For four years.
X小姐 你的生活真如柠檬般清新
Ms.X,you lead a lemon fresh life.
我在水池下找到三瓶不同的清洁剂
Found three different  cleansers under the sink.
还把药品柜搜了一遍
Cleaned out the medicine cabinets too.
她刚打赢一场官司 帮那些房子建在 原沼气池上的家庭获得重新安置
You know,she just won a settlement for some families whose housing development was built on  an old methane field.
接触甲烷能解释她的症状
Toxic exposure to methane  could explain this.
我冲浪?
I surf?
我们认识前你就不玩了
You stopped before we met.
你太忙了
You've been too busy.
我们结婚了?
And we're married?
是的
Yes.
不是针对你
All right,it's nothing personal.
我打赌你们第一次见面时 你不是她喜欢的型
Bet she didn't think you were her type back when  you first met either.
我们带她回医院验血验尿 着手治疗
We'll take her back to the hospital,test her blood and urine and start treatment.
我没事
I'm all right.
- 怎么了? - 我不知道
- What happened? - I don't know.
我的脚突然麻痹了
My foot suddenly went numb.
她尿裤子了
Her pants are wet.
尿失禁
Urinary incontinence.
她复杂部分性癫痫发作
She's having complex partial seizures.
不是甲烷导致
This isn't methane.
- 篮子不用拿了 我们得给她做... - 癫痫?
- You can leave the bucket.We need to get her to-- Seizures?
这是你第二个联系自身情况的诊断了
his is the second diagnosis you've come up with that has a personal resonance for you.
我基于私人问题作医学诊断?
I'm choosing my diagnoses based on personal issues?
你认为她从台阶摔下还尿裤子 是因为Wilson也把她甩了?
You think she fell down the stairs and peed her pants 'cause Wilson dumped her too?
你选择告诉我这个病例 我们分析下
You're choosing to tell me about this case,so let's look at it.
一开始你坚持  是她过去接触的有毒物质致病
First you were fixated on a harmful toxin from her past,
- 也许你联系到你曾接触的毒物 - 中毒是Chase想的
- possibly because you're worried  about a harmful toxin  from your own past. - Chase had the toxin idea.
- 只能说他太纠结我的过往 - 现在你又说是癫痫紊乱?
- Maybe he's obsessed with my past. - And now you're talking about a seizure disorder?
这又不是有毒物质
Which is also not a toxin.
但可能是大脑陈旧性损伤导致
But which is most likely caused by an old injury to the brain.
为什么你这么害怕你的过去?
W-why do you see your past as such a threat?
我不仅不害怕它 我还想把它找回来
Not only am I unthreatened by it,I was trying to get it back.
这里有个凹槽
There's a ding mark.
那是件垃圾 来时就有凹槽了
It's a piece of junk.It was dinged when it came in.
本来就有杯印 刮痕 掉漆 还有那仨凹痕没错
Sure,the--the cup marks and the scuffs and the paint and those three chips.
但第四个是新的
This fourth one is new.
我这是当铺 不是给你保管东西的 你到底要还是不要?
I run a pawn shop,not a storage company.Do you want it or not?
应该就这些了
That should be it.
你说你当了五本 这儿只有四本
You said you pawned five books.There's only four.
只有这些了
That's all there is.
那本"急性腹痛治疗"呢?
Where's approach  to the acute abdomen?
卖了
Sold it.
- 卖给谁了? - 我不能告诉你
- To? - I can't tell you.
这是规定 我也不想告诉你
It's a law,and it should be.
你这种无赖会追着别人要回来
Crazy bastards like you try to hunt down their stuff.
这一堆多少钱?
How much for the pile?
500块
$500.
- 你说它是垃圾 - 不
- You said it was junk. - No,no.
是你的垃圾 500块-- 不要拉倒
It's your junk.You want it.$500-- take it or leave it.
为什么要回这些东西对你如此重要?
why is it so important that you get your stuff back?
不像其他人...  他们不在乎自己的东西易主
Unlike the rest of humanity... Who's okay when their belongings are taken.
每个人都想留住自己的东西 因为那是自己的
Everyone wants their stuff.That's why it's their stuff.
但没人会付五倍价钱
Everyone doesn't pay five times what it's worth.
我喜欢我的东西
I like my stuff.
Wilson动我都不能忍... 这无关Wilson
I hate it when Wilson moves it-- This is not about Wilson!
说吧
Say it.
我不想说什么
I wasn't gonna say anything.
31 31! 传球!
31,31!Hike!
第一档进攻!
First down!
再来个触地得分
One more,you get a touchdown.
传球!
Hike!
House 你不能持球达阵
House,you can't run  for the touchdown.
传球!
And...Hike!
等等
Wait,wait,wait.Wait.
你只告诉我Wilson出现 却不告诉我他说了什么?
You seriously thought  you were gonna tell me  that Wilson showed up but not tell me what he said?
因为我以为你很聪明 无需我赘言
Because I thought you were a smart guy who didn't need the obvious spelled out to him.
Wilson发现我一天没去办公室
Wilson noticed  that I didn't come to my office all day.
就来找我 确定我没事-- 无聊透顶
He came to find me,wanted to make sure I'm okay-- boring,boring,boring.
你却认为有必要告诉我玩橄榄球的事?
Um,but you thought it was important to tell me about nerf football?
抱歉 你的故事 继续
Sorry.Your story.Continue.
House House 打住! 停!
House,House,stop!Stop,stop,stop.
你没事吧?
You okay?
没事 是我妈的 我四岁时她去世了
Yeah.It was my mother's.She died when I was four.
这是她唯一留下的东西
It's all I have left.
真伤心 Alvie
That's very sad,alvie.
听着 我给你预约了移民听证会
Listen,I set up an immigration hearing.
不 House 我会坐牢或更糟--  被驱逐到多米尼加什么的
No,House,I'm gonna end up in jail or worse-- the Dominican or someplace.
天知道 不
Que se yo.Que no.
有意思
Um,interesting.
你表现得毫不在意他人的感受
You present yourself as,uh,not giving a damn about other people's emotions,
但行动却相反
but your actions  indicate otherwise.
你无视Alvie说他母亲的事 却很关心地去安排听证会
You dismiss alvie's story about his mother,but you cared enough to schedule a hearing.
我只关心了八秒钟
I cared for eight seconds.
注意力就转到了别处
Then I got distracted.
- 喂 - 我们让病人保持清醒12小时
- Yeah. - We've kept the patient up  for 12 hours now.
没有癫痫发作的迹象
No hint  of seizure-like activity.We should shut this down.
试试打闪光灯 增加心理压力
Try a strobe light,add more stress.
- 我想她压力够大了 - 除了工作我们还做其它事吗?
- I think there's plenty  of stress in here. - Don't we ever do anything but work?
- 你跑步 - 那也是辛苦活
- You run. - That's just more work.
就没别的娱乐?
What about fun?
天哪 我们怎么这么无趣?
God,how can we be this boring?
显然 失去记忆
Apparently,without her memory,
病人的人格回到了某种原始状态
the patient's personality has returned to what you might call its natural state.
大学时发生的一件事 改变了她的人生轨迹
Seems she had a wake-up call  while she was at college.
她哥哥死于车祸 她决定要活出生命意义
Her brother died in a car accident.She decided to make her life mean something.
于是进了法学院
Went to law school.
现在这一切都没了
Now that's all gone.
引发改变的记忆消失了... 改变也随之消失
The thing that caused the change is gone... So the change itself is gone.
我就知道 这病例的心理因素 会让你感兴趣
Yeah.I knew the psychological aspects of this case would interest you.
我打赌你已经有结论了 是什么?
Bet you got a theory already.What is it?
和诊断无关
It's not relevant.
什么?
What is it?
为什么关心我的结论?
Why do you care about my theory?
我觉得他...让她觉得很烦
I think he just... Bores her.
她好比新生儿看到自己的未来 但这个未来使她觉得了无生趣
She's at an earlier  stage of development.She's looking  at her grown-up future,and it puts her  to sleep.
如果他只是让她烦了  她会出于礼貌不表现出来
If he just bored her,she'd hide it to be polite.
他们的问题在于 就像你和我  House 他们不在历史的同一页
Their problem is synchronicity.Just like you and me,House,they're not on the same page.
他向她述说以往的共同经历
He talks to her like someone he shares history with.
但在她看来 他只是个陌生人 拼命向她亲近
But from her point of view,he's a stranger forcing intimacy on her.
她当然不会喜欢他 他帮不上忙
Of course she doesn't like him.He's not helping.
他感到自己正失去自己的妻子 于是越发急躁
He can feel  he's losing his wife,and it makes him come on stronger.
他差点真失去她了
He almost did lose his wife.
呼吸问题由肺部积液过量导致
The breathing problem was caused by fluid overload in the lungs.
尿崩症
Diabetes insipidus.
尿崩症由下视丘损伤引起
And the d.I. Came from damage to the hypothalamus.
下视丘在这里  因此尿崩和失禁同时出现
Hypothalamus here,hence the d.I. And incontinence.They mingle here.
此处导致全面性遗忘 这是运动皮层-- 导致脚部麻痹
There's the global amnesia.And the motor cortex-- that's the foot paralysis.
什么同时导致以上问题?
What do they all have in common?
你说这些是要糊弄我
Okay,now you're just  doing this to mess with me.
这鉴别诊断和你的问题有何关系?
What possible relevance does this differential have to your problems?
这能得出牛海绵状脑炎的结论
It ends with a diagnosis of spongiform encephalitis.
我说服手下切掉病人大脑一部分
I convinced the team to cut out part of this woman's brain.
- 你对此不感兴趣? - 不
- That's not interesting to you? - No.
即便切的是杏仁核? (控制恐惧)
Not even if it's the amygdala?
会让她丧失所有长期记忆
She'll lose all her long-term memory.
你无非想强调 割裂别人的过去 与你想逃避自己的过去无关
Well,this is where you tell me that being cavalier with someone else's past has nothing to do with avoiding your own past.
这病例根本与你不相干
The case is irrelevant.
你只是觉得...有趣
You just found it,uh... Interesting.
心理医师不是该循循善诱吗?
Aren't therapists supposed to be nurturing?
手册里没规定
Nowhere... Is that in the manual.
你接受治疗一年了
Look,you--you've been in therapy for a year.
你很清楚我让你说说自己 是想让你说那些影响你--
You know when I ask you to talk about anything,I mean anything that affects you--
使你沮丧 抓狂 轻松或高兴的事
what upset you,what made you mad or relieved or joyful.
但在我看来 这病例对你毫无影响
You want me to believe that this case means nothing?
那...
Then,um...
为什么我要听呢?
Why should I listen to it?
这段时间你也收钱?
Are you charging me for this time?
嗯
Yes.
真荒谬
This is ridiculous.
那是什么?
What's that?
你胳膊上的?
On the back of your arm?
只是瘀伤 我跌倒了
It's just a bruise.And I fell.
你记得自己跌倒了?
You remember falling?
不
No.
我喝醉了... 没法保持平衡
I was drunk... Hence the balance issues.
看来你倒在某人靴尖上了
Well,it looks like you fell on the tip of someone's boot.
我说的话激怒了别人
I said something that someone objected to.
- 如果你不记得 你怎么... - 一般别人打我都是这原因
- Well,if you don't remember,then how can you-- it's usually  the way it is  when someone hits me.
你倒地后 他们踹你固然可恶 但这可恶不是没由头的
People who kick when you're down are jerks,but they're generally not irrational jerks.
你喝醉卷入酒吧打斗 醒来忘了 你还坚持说你没事?
Yogot drunk enough to get into a bar fight and not remember,and you've been insisting that everything's fine?
为什么出去买醉?
W-why--why go out and get blind drunk?
你想找人打架?
Were you looking  for a fight?
我不知道
I don't know.
你做错了什么?
What have you screwed up?
- 什么? - 你说你被打
- What? - You say that when  you've been hit in the past,
是因为你挑起事端 就是说你知道其危险性
it's because you provoked it with something that you said,which means you're well aware of the risks.
所以某程度上 你是故意去酒吧讨打
So on some level,you were in that bar looking  for someone to hurt you.
人们惩罚自己  往往因为他做了 或没做某些事
Logically,people punish themselves  for something they did or something they didn't do.
你到底做错了什么?
So what... Did you screw up?
我不知道
I don't know.
好吧 也许是有问题
Okay,there may be a problem.
很好... 我们谈谈Wilson
All right... Let's talk about Wilson.
我告诉他 你的书沾染了炭疽孢子
I told him your book was contaminated with Anthrax spores.
还给了他300块
Then I gave him $300.
买家的地址
The address of the buyer.
我不该这么急着赶走你
Maybe I was hasty in asking you to move out.
何不和我还有Sam多住一阵?
Why don't you stay with me and Sam for a little while?
没必要这么急
There's no need to hurry things.
为什么挽留我?
What prompted this?
你从Mayfield出来后不能一个人呆着
Look,the whole idea was that after Mayfield,you wouldn't be on your own.
我们一起住 我可以随时和你通气---
I can touch base with you a lot more easily if you're staying with me than--
看在上帝份上 Wilson
God's sake,Wilson.
你只能越描越黑
You really span  the chasm  from wishy to washy.
既然唱了白脸就唱下去
If you're gonna be an ass,be an ass.
狠心到底
Stick with it.
他只想安抚你 你为什么这么苛刻?
Why were you being  so hard on the guy,when he was being conciliatory?
算了吧
Come on.
是Cuddy利用他的内疚 让他这样做的
Cuddy played on his guilt.She put him up to this.
你怎么知道?
How do you know that?
你怎知不是他自己的主意?
How do you know this wasn't entirely his own idea?
原因有二--  第一 他想和Sam过二人世界
Two reasons--  first,he wants to create the perfect environment to be with Sam.
想我走有段时间了
He's been thinking about  asking me to leave for a while.
好容易说出口  他会突然改主意? 不可能
Finally he does it and immediately turns around and changes his mind--no.
他肯定和某人谈了
He talked to somebody.
也许是Sam
Maybe it was Sam.
也有这个可能
Yeah,that's a possibility.
我希望这是我最后一段认真的感情
I want this to be the last serious relationship I ever have.
我希望这就是我的归宿
I want this to be the one.
我也是
Me too.
House在哪?
Where's House?
没了他 这还有什么意思?
It's not as meaningful without him.
好吧...不是Sam
Okay,um... Not Sam.
但还是不能说明为什么是Cuddy
Uh,that still doesn't answer  why Cuddy.
因为他们谈论过我
Because they've been talking about me.
她打来叫我去查看病人 她从不无缘无故这么做
She called me  to check on the patient,which she never does without a reason.
- 我问为什么 她说... - 她是律师 House
- I asked why,and she said... - She's a barracuda attorney,House.
对待这种病人 我们要小心
These are the kind of patients we like to keep happy.
眼下 这病人记得"法律" 二字怎么写就算走运了
Right now the patient's lucky if she can spell jurisprudence.
是的 但当她恢复记忆
Yeah,but when  she gets that memory back,
这也是我们努力的目标 她就会写"官司"二字了
which we are trying  to make happen,she'll be able  to spell lawsuit.
我只想给你通个气儿
I'm just touching base.
通个气
Touching base.
Wilson也用了同样的字眼
Wilson used exactly the same phrase.
算计我是她最爱的消遣
Colluding about me is her favorite pastime.
好吧 你认为他们谈过了
Okay,you think they talked.
那你认为他们说了什么?
How do you think that conversation went?
我很担心House
I'm worried about House.
我也是
Me too.
你就不能等等吗?
Couldn't you have waited?
要他回到从前的公寓  靠自己过活 未免为时太早
It's way too early for him to be on his own,back in the old apartment.
- 你凭什么觉着他能应付? - 我说了帮他找个新住处
- What makes you think he can handle it? - I offered to find him a new place.
你得把他接回去
You have to let him  back into your condo.
Sam和我刚把他弄出去
Sam and I just got him  out of the condo.
你知道House是什么人 他有自毁倾向
You know what House is like.He's self-destructive.
没人监管他 又会重新嗑药
Without constant supervision,he's gonna slide back into drugs.
如果你不干 就得我来了
If you're not watching him,I've got to.
是啊
Yeah.
他们不信任你
So they don't trust you.
他们认为你会重蹈覆辙
They assume you'll fail.
这是他们的忧虑 还是你的?
Are these their fears or yours?
我们把灯打开吧?
Let's turn on the lights,Hmm?
也点亮你的心灯
In your brain.
可能他们真谈过了 但...  你怎知道不是这样?
Maybe they did talk about you,but... How do you know it didn't happen like this?
- 我很担心House - 为什么?
- I'm worried about House. - Why?
自打从Mayfield出院以后 这是他第一次独立生活
It's the first time he'll be on his own since Mayfield.
你过分保护他了 House不需生活在温室里
Now you're being  overprotective.House doesn't need  to be wrapped in cotton wool.
你很清楚这点 否则不会叫他搬出去
But you know that,or you wouldn't have asked him to move out.
好吧
Okay.
我想是我想多了
I guess this is really about me.
但...我觉得自己很混
It's just... I feel like a jerk.
当然 Sam和我到头来还是会独处 但我没给他时间去适应
Sure,Sam and I are gonna want to be on our own eventually,but I kind of  sprang this on him.
我该让他别着急着走 呆到能独立生活为止
The right way  would have been  to just tell him  to take as long as he needed,that there's no hurry.
过程拖的再长 结果还不是一样
So it's not what you did,but how you did it.
但对友情来说 过程很重要
That matters in a friendship.
我必须作出补救
I need to fix this.
你让他搬回来不就好了
Why don't you talk to him about moving back in?
只是通个气儿
Just touch base.
病人在同意书上有争论
We're having a consent issue with the patient.
等等 Taub不该在这
Wait a minute.Taub's not here.
- 不 他在 - 病人在同意书上有争议
- Yeah,he is. - We're having a consent issue with the patient.
Taub跑到我想象的 Wilson和Cuddy对话中干什么?
What's Taub doing in my imaginary version of a scene with Wilson and Cuddy?
你的想象该结束了 因为根本不靠谱
Your version needed to be ended,'cause it's crap.
里头充斥着脉脉温情  相信我最终会走上正途
It's all sweetness and light and... Faith that I'm gonna choose the right path.
听起来就像Wilson
Yeah,that sounds like Wilson.
我的想象是有事实支持的
I have as much evidence  for mine  as you do for yours.
据我所知 Wilson是你朋友
I know Wilson's your friend.
他开始担心这么做是不对的
So he could be wondering if he did right by you.
我也相信 如果他不确定你能独立生活
And I know he wouldn't have asked you to move out in the first place unless
一开始就不会叫你搬出去
he was convinced you could handle life on your own.
但据我所知 他和Cuddy曾背着我  商量怎么对付我
And I know that he and Cuddy have gone behind my back before to strategize about the House problem.
两个版本都有可信之处
So there's truth in both versions.
但你宁愿相信让你难过那个
But you choose to focus on the parts that make you uncomfortable.
那么...
So...
为什么你和Wilson是朋友?
Why are you and Wilson... Friends?
你认为这样的友情已是你的极限?
Do you think this friendship is the best you can do?
Wilson不是个安慰奖
Wilson is not a consolation prize.
你在替他说话
There... You're defending him.
一分钟前 他还是密谋算计你的埃古  (出自奥赛罗)
And a minute ago,he was skulking around in the background like some sort of manipulative iago.
他是我的朋友
He's my friend.
那你看重他什么呢?
So what do you value in him?
我可以随心所欲对他说任何话  他也不会抛弃我
I can say whatever I want to him,and he'll never leave.
他这不是抛弃你了
He's sort of leaving.
至少他不能经常陪着你了 因为他把Sam放在第一位
At least,he won't be around as much... Because he's putting Sam first.
暂时而已
For now.
他们分手后 就会让我搬回去
After the divorce,he'll probably ask me to move in again.
我目光比较长远
I take the long view.
你对Wilson说了吗?
You say that to Wilson?
开玩笑么? 这种论调他还不恨死我
Are you kidding?That's the kind of remark that leads people to hate you.
也许你一开始是对的
Uh,maybe you've been right from the beginning.
不是Wilson的问题
Maybe this isn't about Wilson.
我好容易跟上你节奏 你却说这个?
You say that now that I finally agree with you?
你非得和我唱反调吗?
Do you just argue the opposite of whatever I say?
我不是说Wilson的事没影响你
I don't mean the Wilson thing doesn't,uh,bother you,
但听来 他是你最可靠的朋友
uh,but it sounds like he's the closest you can come to a safe relationship.
要搞砸这段友谊没那么容易
You'd have to do something major to screw it up.
这星期你还做了什么?
Um,what--what else have you been involved in this week?
为什么你要惩罚自己?
What would you want to punish yourself for?
我说了 我不知道
I told you,I don't know.
好的 我们换个角度
Okay,um,let's approach it from a different angle.
你有没让任何人因为任何事 而生你的气?
Have you gotten any other people angry at you over anything?
有 所以才叫做平常的一周
Well,yeah.That's why I called it an ordinary week.
好的 说说看
Okay.Tell me about it.
你会失去大脑一部分
You'd be losing  a part of your brain.
这是我的大脑 为什么我没权签同意书?
It is my brain.Why is it not my right to consent?
对不起 但...必要的话我会诉诸法律
I'm sorry,but...  I'll take this to court if necessary.
Sidney目前没能力为自己作决定
All right,Sidney's in no position to make decisions about herself right now.
她甚至不知自己是谁
She doesn't even know who she is.
我看过同意书了  我明白它意思 我想做这手术
I read your consent form,and I understood it.I want the surgery.
她怎么不同意?
Why wouldn't she?
当然她愿意冒险永远失去记忆
Of course she's willing to risk losing her memories permanently.
她不知那些记忆有多重要
She has no idea how important those memories are.
她知道这意味着什么吗?
Does she even know what risk is?
她根本毫无损失可言
She's never lost anything.
不做手术 她会失去一切
Without the surgery,she'll lose everything.
朊毒体感染会持续扩散 摧毁她大脑
The prion infection will continue to advance and destroy her whole brain.
一定还有其它方法
Well,there has to be another way.
求你了
Please.
我代表我妻子说这番话 她不在这里 不能为自己辩护
I'm speaking for my wife,the wife I lived with for four years who isn't here  and can't defend herself.
House医生 你在听吗?
Dr.House,are you listening?
不用争论了 已经不重要了
Well,you can stop arguing,'cause it doesn't matter anymore.
看心率的变化
Look at the variability in the heart rate.
脑炎已经扩散到脑干
The s.E. Has spread into the brain stem.
不管那是什么 你还是可以把它切掉
W-wherever it is,you--you can still cut it out.
不 我们不能切掉脑干
No. We can't cut the brain stem.
病毒扩散得太快 手术已经没用了 我想这场争论你赢了
This thing's moving too quickly.Surgery's no longer an option,which I guess means you've won.
恭喜
Congratulations.
植入心脏起搏器 给她化疗
Put in a pacer and start her on chemo and radiation.
这救不了她 只能让她多活几周 看能不能记起她是谁
It won't cure her,but it'll buy a couple weeks so she can find out who she is before she dies.
太残酷了
That was pretty rough.
你总这么通知病人的吗?
Do you always break the news  to your patients that way?
还是你为我剪辑的版本?
Or were you  short-handing it for me?
丈夫很白痴
Husband was being an idiot.
这是他自找的
Well,he was asking for it.
但惩罚他的同时也惩罚了妻子
But,um,to punish him you have to punish the wife too.
为什么他让你这么生气?
Why--why did he make you so angry,Hmm?
因为他不配合你?
Because he didn't want to cooperate with you?
他宁愿冒妻子的生命危险来保住婚姻
He'd rather risk his wife's life than their marriage.
当人们失去所爱时 就会失去理智
People's brains stop working when they think they're gonna lose someone they love.
你腿疼?
Your leg hurt?
还好
It's all right.
好吧 你还惹毛了什么人?
Okay. Anyone else you pissed off?
50块买那本书
50 bucks for the book.
想都别想
Forget it.
你只花25块钱 已经赚了一倍
You paid $25.That's 100% return.
我付了25没错 但这是本难得一见 有百年历史且完好无损的外科教材
That's what I paid.But it's a rare surgical text,nearly 100 years old-- plate's in mint condition.
值好几千大洋呢
That book's worth several thousand dollars.
2000 我给你写支票
$2,000-- I'll write you a check.
真诱人 面对现实吧 值钱东西逃不过我的眼睛
Nice try.Face it-- I had the wit to recognize something valuable when I saw it.
在人类进化的漫长赛跑中 我是最终赢家
In the great darwinian race,I get my just reward.
你只能挂在半路
You become roadkill.
House 经过图书馆能停下么?
Yo,House,you want to stop by the library?
我有本书要还 哎-呦-喂!
'Cause I got a book to return.Ta-ka-plow!
* 老教授想囤积居奇 * * 三脚看门狗岂能阻挡Alive *
*Old Professor tried to hoard/hog * *you can't stop alvie with no guard-ass dog *
被人看见没?
anyone see you?
教授看见我在车道上走  跟我说玫瑰还得施肥
Yeah,prof saw me walking down the driveway.He said the roses need more fertilizer.
我不知大脑上还有个希望区
I didn't know there was a section of the brain just for hope.
很小很小一块
It's very,very tiny.
我们用荧光镜导入了心脏起搏器
We used fluoroscopy to guide pacemaker placement in the patient's heart.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
迅速恶化的扩张性心肌病
Rapidly progressive dilated cardiomyopathy.
不是牛海绵状脑炎  无论是什么 不止大脑有
This isn't s.E.,and whatever it is,it's not just in her brain.
在攻击她全身
It's attacking her whole body.
你为House干活? 咱俩是队友
You work for House?I guess we're teammates.
酷不?
Isn't that cool?
你好
Hello.
- Juan Alvarez? - 搞什么啊?
- Juan alvarez? - What the hell?
我们要拘捕你 这是遣返令
We're taking you into custody--  deportation order.
我是公民 你们歧视波多黎各人
I'm a citizen.You're disrespecting Puerto Rico.
你要是公民 怎么不去听证会?
If you're a citizen,why'd you miss your hearing?
你叫他们来的?
You called them?
怎么回事?
What's going on?
我们尽力使她的心脏保持稳定
We're trying to stabilize her heart.
可她仍心动过速且低血压
She's still tachy and hypotensive.
大脑 心脏 迅速恶化
Brain,heart,and rapidly progressing.
心内膜炎 慢性感染导致脑内血块
Endocarditis--slow-moving  infection in her heart  throws clots to her brain.
不跟你玩了
I'm not talking to you.
你咋能背叛我?
How could you turn me in?
剧烈运动抑制免疫系统 使感染蔓延
Her extreme exercise  suppresses her immune system,allows the infection to smolder.
或是旧有感染复发 比如肺结核
Or allows an old infection  to reactivate it--t.B.
给她用多药疗法
Start her on a multidrug regimen.
我不喜欢你了 House 我讨厌你
I don't like you,House.I hate you.
就算静脉注射抗生素  也要时间发挥药效
Even I.V. Antibiotics  will take time to work.
提醒下你 禁止在法庭用手机
A general reminder--the use of cell phones is prohibited.
手术时直接给肺部注射第一剂
Give her the first dose directly into the lungs in the O.R.
趁我还没以藐视法庭罪逮捕你
Before the less gentle  arrest for contempt.
在隔离室里给她照紫外线
Put her in an isolation room with U.V. light.
顺便查下自己 你们都接触过她
And get yourselves tested.You've all been exposed.
第4378号案件
Docket number 4378.
你是?
You are?
Alvarez先生的医生
I am Mr.alvarez's doctor.
法官大人 DNA检测证明了 Juan Alvarez的母系血统
Your honor,DNA evidence proving the matriarchal lineage of Juan alvarez.
我妈的DNA还健在?
My mother's DNA was still on that cross?
可能
It could be.
你造假?
You faked it?
不止我 你连他们都忽悠了!
It wasn't just me.You lied to them too!
这方面我比你牛
I'm better at it than you are.
我这就去重刷你的公寓  让窗帘和地毯一个颜色!
I'm gonna repaint your whole apartment now,make the drapes  match the carpet now!
肺积液 血氧饱和下降
Lungs sound wet.O-2 sats are dropping.
得插管 输利尿磺胺
May need to tube her.Grab some I.V. Furosemide.
慢着 慢
Wait,wait.
她不行了 得插管了
She's crashing.We need to get her  on a vent.
她脚踝有东西
There's something on her ankle.
纹身
Tattoo.
"Eddie woule go"
"Eddie would go.
是冲浪流行语 肯定是她早年纹的
" It's a surfing phrase.Must be from her earlier life.
她想除掉它 但只去掉了皮肤表层的
She tried to get it removed,but they only took off the top layers of skin.
深层组织里还有墨水残留
The ink is still in the deeper layers.
引发过敏反应
Set off an allergic reaction.
开始长跑前她还好好的
She was fine  until she started  the long-distance  running.
剧烈的马拉松运动抑制了 她的免疫系统 引发过敏反应
The ultra-marathoning modified her immune system,set off the allergic reaction.
做个全厚皮片移植 就没事了
We did a full thickness skin graft,and she'll be okay.
最后还是你对了
So you were right... In the end.
是她过去惹的祸
It was her past.
她恢复记忆了吗?
Did she get  her memory back?
还没
Not yet.
她会吗?
Will she?
- 无从得知 - 我想玫瑰是我最爱
- No way to know. - I think roses  are my favorite.
我应该告诉过你吧
But I guess I told you that at some point.
不记得了
I don't remember.
他待她如初遇一般
He's treating her  as though they just met.
他在重新追求她
He's courting her.
谁给他出的主意?
Whose idea was that?
他当初还拧着来 突然变套路了
He was doing the opposite of everything he should.Suddenly he's changed.
- Taub觉得也许- - 这是你的主意
- Taub thought it might--  that was your idea.
你特地问我对他俩的事怎么看
And you asked me what I thought was going on between them.
困扰你的是他们之间的关系
It's their relationship that's on your mind.
你关心这病例 是因为这段关系
That's why you've been thinking about this case-- relationships.
Wilson没了 Alvie补上
Lost one with Wilson,gained one with alvie.
谁说的
Not exactly.
Alvie?
想说说纸条写了什么吗?
You gonna tell me  what the note said?
我帮Alvie摆平麻烦 他很感激
Alvie was very grateful that I'd gotten him out of trouble.
他能去菲尼克斯找他表哥 不用担心被移民局带走了
It allowed him to go stay with his cousin in Phoenix without worrying about immigration looking for him there.
你没想过他会留下来
You didn't think he was gonna stay forever.
- 没 - 接下来怎么了?
- No. - What happened next?
没怎么
Nothing happened next.
我说完了
That's all I got.
关系
Relationships.
伯格曼
Bergman.
- 你想让我说什么? - 我不知道
- What do you want me to say? - I don't know.
这是你亲口说的--
You're the one  who said the thing--
你受某段关系困扰 才去生事打架
something about relationships made you go out and provoke a fight.
Wilson和Sam打得火热
Wilson and Sam have a relationship.
你并不为他们高兴
You're not thrilled about it.
他们很幸福
They're happy.
我干嘛要去搅和?
Why should I screw that up?
每个人都很幸福
Everyone's happy.
他们都搬到了一起 Wilson和Sam Cuddy和Lucas
Everyone's moving in together-- Wilson and Sam,Cuddy and Lucas.
- 就连Alvie- - Cuddy和Lucas同居了?
- Even alvie's-- Cuddy and Lucas are moving in together?
这你可没说
You didn't mention that.
这事儿他们之前就谈过
They talked about moving in together before.
没啥劲爆的
It's not big news.
Cuddy...
Cuddy
Cuddy.
急性腹痛治疗...
Approach  to the acute abdomen...
作者 Ernest T.Cuddy医生 和你那位Cuddy有关系么?
Written by Ernest t.Cuddy,m.D. Any relation  to your Cuddy?
是她太爷爷
Her great-grandfather.
我留着很多年了... 想找个特殊场合送她
I've had it for years... Always meant to give it to her for a special occasion.
比如...乔迁之喜?
Like her... Housewarming?
就是个礼物而已
It's just a gift.
你爱的女人推开你 投向他人怀抱
A woman you care about  is taking one step further away from you and closer to someone else?
你提都不提 想必对你打击沉重
I-I think I can safely say yes,it's significant  if you don't mention it.
你训斥病人的丈夫  是因为在他身上找到共鸣
You were willing to punish the husband of your patient because you identified with him.
他也是痛失所爱之人
He was also losing someone he loved.
因为不属于我的女人和别人同居  而跑出去找打
I'm not gonna go out and get hammered because a woman I'm not even with is moving in with someone.
我也太可悲了
That'd be pathetic.
去你大爷的
To hell with this.
我当初来找你 说想得到快乐 我依足了你的建议去做
When I first came to you,I told you that I wanted to be happy,and I followed your advice.
可我还是这么痛苦
And instead,I'm just miserable.
这到底管什么用?
How is this working for me?
这需要时间
It takes time.
都一年了 你说的我照单全做 如今他们全幸福美满了
For a year,I've done everything you've asked,and everybody else is happy.
我上了悲催跑步机 你却在一旁看热闹
I run on my treadmill.You just sit there and watch.
你就是个神棍
You're a faith healer.
利用人们的信仰
You take advantage of people who want to believe.
其实什么法力都没有
But there's nothing in your bag of tricks.
House...
不管答案是什么 你都给不了
Whatever the answer is,you don't have it.